In this clip, we are going to be turning our bag right side out and making buttonholes along the two seams so we can use those to loop through our drawstring.
Go ahead and turn your bag inside out.
At the very top you want to figure out where you want to put your botton holes.
What we are going to be doing is folding the top over and making a little casing the ribbon will slip through.
Fold it over about 3/4 of inch and turn to the right side of the bag.
Place a pin about 1/4 inch down and then 1/4 inch down from that pin is where we will be doing the button hole.
Make sure once you fold over for the casing, you won't have anything sticking out.
Do the same thing on the other side.
You can even measure how far done.
In this case it's 1 1/4 inch.
Go to the other seam and measure down 1 1/4 inches.
Put in your pin and then another pin 1/4 inch down from there.
We are just doing a really small buttonhole because this rattail we are going to use to slip through is very thin.
Make sure they both measure up and I also like to fold them together.
The measurement is off just a little bit and I will fix that.
We are going to do a four-step buttonhole.
Switch out to your buttonhole foot, which looks like this.
Line up your fabric in the very center and to the top.
Put it on the first step of the botton hole.
Four step button holes will have a picture, sometimes its arrow or sometimes its number or sometimes it's labled A, B, C, D.